# Mengxue Xu Full Stack Engineer

Email: mxu4321@gmail.com, Github: github.com/mxu4321, LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mengxuexu/

# **Summary**

No Visa Sponsorship required. Certified full stack engineer with 2 Master's (Engineering Mgmt., HR Mgmt.) 5 years' experience in both enterprise and start-up focusing on the following:

Full Stack Web Development, Business Analytics, Data Analytics and Visualization, Human Resources Skills & tools: Javascript, Express.js, VScode, Node.js, SQL, Salesforce, Workday, JIRA, Lucidchart, Excel.

Languages: English, Chinese Mandarin, Japanese, Cantonese

### **Work Experience**

#### Full Stack Bootcamp Trainee, UC Berkeley Extension

10/2022 - est. 04/2023

- Designed and developed front end projects with but not limited to HTML, CSS, javascript, bootstrap, jQuery, APIs on Github
- Prototyped and tested back end projects using node.is, jest.js, express.is, MySQL, heroku, MongoDB, react.is.

#### Caregiving, Sweet Home, Hayward, CA

Mar 2021 - Present

Act as the Chief Home Officer and empowers everybody including two cats to have a better life.

#### Store Manager, New Life Acupuncture Clinic, Redwood City, CA

Mar 2020 - Feb 2021

- Built and launched the **online reservation system** for the clinic that enables the customers to make/modify/cancel reservations based on their profiles.
- Standardized and digitalized customer profiles and clinic documents into the CRM system.
- Executed marketing campaigns for existing and new customers, increasing customer base by 400+.
- Established, maintained relationships with referral sources, networks, and local communities to drive growth.

# Program Manager - Placement, MentorX Corp., Fremont, CA

Jan 2018 - Feb 2020

- Drove and lead 5 people **scrum** team (with **offshore**) to launch **SuperAcademy** featuring 80+ courses/tutorials, 500K views as an add-on product to enhance our tailored services to attract and satisfy customers.
- Initialized, analyzed and supervised the Student Huaxiang (Digital Reporting and Forecasting) project, turning the
  manual non-scalable team status report meetings into automated, digitized reports, forecasts and presentations to
  increase internal productivity. (Average time spent on reporting dropped from 3 hours to 20 mins /week/member)
- Self-learned Salesforce Admin and guide other team members to adapt to CRM and standardize the processes.
- Created and refined the analytical models to support essential business decision making including student churning, cost analysis, partner comparison and investor relationship with **Salesforce, MySQL and Tableau**.
- Worked with Engineers to configure and roll out Workday for Payroll, Benefits and Performance Evaluation.
- Data entry and assessment of 500+ sales opps/leads and 100+ partners.
- Student and channel survey for pain point discovery saved 35% in acquisition cost + 30% less churn rate.

#### HR Specialist, Gate Gourmet, San Francisco

2015 - 2017

- Strong knowledge of hire-to-retire, compensation plans, benefits administration and performance evaluation.
- Familiar with Ultipro and Taleo as the hiring portal for the full cycle hiring process.
- Increased the survey participation rate by providing wrapped gifts and giveaways.

## Flight Attendant, China Southern Airlines, China

2011 – 2012

800+ domestic flying hours assisting passengers including catering and safety procedures.

## Education

Master of Science in Engineering ManagementInternational Technological University, San Jose, CA2018Master of Science in Human Resource ManagementGolden Gate University, San Francisco, CA2015Bachelor of Science in International TradingHenan Normal University, Henan, China2012CertificationCertificationCertification

UC Berkeley Extension - Full Stack Flex Program

Japanese Language Proficiency Test (JLPT) N1

Salesforce Certified Admin from Salesforce

Product Management Certificate from Product School

Certified Scrum Master from Scrum Alliance.org

10/2022 - est. 04/2023

02/2022

04/2023

02/2020

12/2019